The binding is the device that physically holds you to the snowboard.
The binding pretty much looks a lot like this.
It has either a bone out strap; and a strap that goes over your toe.
It might have a bone out strap with a toe strap like this that goes over the end of your toes.
It might have one pad on top for both the bone out and the toe and your high back will fold down so you can enter through the back.
It might not have any straps on it what so ever.
In which those are called step ins.
You have a prong on the side of your boot.
They might not even be snowboard bindings at all if you have an alpine or racing board, because yours are going to look a lot similar to a ski binding.
Flat to the board and you're not going to use a snowboarding boot.
You're going to use a hard plastic boot.